crystalknows.com 2019-12-17

# Privacy Policy

Your privacy and security are important to Crystal Project, Inc. (“Crystal”). As a result, we have developed strict internal processes developed to maintain your data in a secure environment.

For purposes of this Privacy Policy, “Personal Data” means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person including name, identification number, location data, an online identifier or to one or more factors specific to the physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural or social identity of that natural person. Personal Data may include Sensitive Information; and “Subscription Service” means the particular edition and elements of Crystal Project's Crystal applications, tools and platform subscribed to by Customer under an Order Form, and developed, operated, and maintained by Crystal Project, accessible via www.crystalknows.com or another designated URL, and any ancillary online or offline products and services provided to Customer by Crystal Project, to which Customer is being granted access pursuant to this Agreement and an Order Form. The Subscription Service includes the Crystal Project Content, and does not include training services, consulting services, and Third-Party Products. All other terms used in this Privacy Policy that are not otherwise defined in this Privacy Policy have the meanings ascribed to them in the Terms of Service (available here: https://www.crystalknows.com/tos).

Crystal is a platform where people can fill out personality tests and share their personality profile. We also use public data to provide personality predictions, based on the person's writing style.

The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to explain (1) what data we collect from you, (2) how we collect, use, process, store, and share your data, and (3) who we share your data with.

We collect and use the following information to provide, improve and protect our Services:

## **Personal Information**

We may collect, and associate with your account, information like your name, email address, postal address, phone number, demographics, mobile device ID, precise location data, and billing and payment information.

## **Connected Accounts**

When you use Crystal and the Subscription Services, you may grant us access to third-party applications like Gmail or LinkedIn (such applications, the “Connected Accounts”). We query, store, process, and transmit information related to your Connected Accounts in connection with providing the Subscription Services. If you decide to connect your Google Calendar to receive meeting insights, we lookup the individuals associated with the meeting in our database. If you decide to connect your Outlook Calendar to receive meeting insights, we lookup the individuals associated with the meeting in our database (for both Google Calendar and Outlook Calendar, we do not store past meetings on our servers). When using data from Connected Accounts, we distinguish between public data and private data.

(i) Public data, which is information that individuals have chosen to make public on the Internet, and which anyone can find using one of the major search engines. We aggregate public data, analyze the text content, detect communication style and personality assumptions, and show this information to everyone who uses Crystal and the Subscription Services. Specific data on which we base our assumptions and determinations is not made available through our Subscription Services; only the assumptions and determinations based on such data is made available through our Subscription Services.

(ii) Private data, which is privileged information to which only you have access. In order to provide users briefings, we may need to process this data (only as listed in the “With Whom” section); however, the private data itself will never be displayed to any other Crystal user or publicly unless you explicitly ask us to.

## **Usage**

We collect information from and about the devices you use to access the Subscription Services. This includes things like IP addresses, the type of browser and device you use, the languages used by your browser or device, the web page you visited before coming to our sites, and identifiers associated with your devices, such as location. Your devices (depending on their settings) may also transmit location information to the Subscription Services. Most mobile devices allow you to turn off location services.

## **Cookies**

We use cookies and similar technology to automatically collect data from you to provide, improve, protect and promote our Subscription Services. For example, cookies help us with things like remembering your username for your next visit, understanding how you are interacting with our Subscription Services, and improving them based on that information. You can set your browser to not accept cookies, but this may limit your ability to use the Subscription Services.

## **Publicly Available Information**

The Subscription Services may allow you to connect and share your actions, comments, contacts, and information publicly with friends, relatives, and members of your professional network. Please be mindful of your personal privacy needs and the privacy needs of others as you choose whom to connect with and what to share and make public. We cannot control the privacy or security of information you choose to make public or share with others. Please contact those sites and services directly if you want to learn about their privacy practices. Additionally, certain Subscription Services utilize publicly available sources of information to provide assumptions and determinations about third parties. Because certain of our Subscription Services provide information to Customers or Users about third parties who may be unaware that our Subscription Service is collecting publicly available information about them, it is of utmost importance that we take appropriate measures to protect such third parties’ rights and freedoms. To that end, we ensure that we only use information that such third party has made publicly available and for which such third party does not have a reasonable expectation of privacy, that such information is only stored for so long as is necessary to provide the Subscription Services to our Customers and Users, and that only our assumptions and determinations based on that data, as opposed to the specific data itself, is disclosed to our Customers and Users.

## **Deletion/Changes/Updates**

If you delete your Crystal account, we will delete all of your personal information and private data. Please note: (1) there might be some latency in deleting this information from our servers and back-up storage; and (2) we may retain this information if necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, or enforce our agreements. You have the right to request, at any time, Crystal to delete, update, change, or alter your Crystal account and any other information Crystal may have collected from or about you. To delete, update, change, or alter your account or any information that Crystal may have collected from or about you, contact us at hello@crystalknows.com.

We use your data collected through the Subscription Services for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy. For example, we may use your data to:

  * Offer you or provide you with other products and services through the Subscription Services;
  * Operate and improve our Subscription Services, our applications, and other products and services;
  * Make assumptions and/or determinations about you or members of your network. In connection with such collection we may use automated processing techniques, in combination with manual decision making, to make certain determinations about you and your preferences. If you have any questions pertaining to our use of automated processing techniques, please contact us at hello@crystalknows.com.
  * Display relevant advertising;
  * Respond to your comments and questions and to provide customer service
  * Send you information relating to our products and services, including technical notices, updates, security alerts, and support and administrative messages;
  * Communicate with you about products and services offered by us, our affiliates, and certain of our select partners;
  * Authenticate credit care or debit card account information; and
  * Protect, investigate, and deter against fraudulent, unauthorized, or illegal activity.

By providing you mobile phone number and/or email address, you expressly consent to receive direct dial calls, autodialed and prerecorded calls, text messages, and or email messages from us regarding our products and services.

We employ appropriate technical and organizational measures to help protect your Personal Data and any other information that Crystal collects from or about you. We have team members dedicated to keeping your information secure and testing for vulnerabilities. We also continue to work on features to keep your information safe. However, while we attempt to protect all information you send to us and we maintain to provide Crystal and the Subscription Services to you, please note that no connection through the Internet and data storage facilities are entirely immune from unauthorized hacking and access, and so you should use Crystal and the Subscription Services with discretion. You can help us by protecting your username and password and using Crystal and the Subscription Services only through secure networks.

Your private data will be kept secure and private as detailed above. It may need to be processed by other people or third party purposes. We will only share such information for the following purposes.

## **Others working for Crystal**

For quality and technical support purposes, select Crystal employees may review your data. These employees will access your information only to perform tasks on behalf of and in compliance with this Privacy Policy. Crystal employees with access to your data are bound to Crystal by obligations of confidentiality sufficient to ensure compliance with the requirements set forth in this Privacy Policy.

## **Service Providers**

Crystal uses trusted third party cloud service providers to help us provide, improve, protect, and promote our Subscription Services (for example, Google Analytics uses cookies to help us understand how users interact with cyrstalknows.com). These third parties will access your information only to perform tasks on our behalf and in compliance with this Privacy Policy.

## **Payment and Billing**

To use certain Subscription Services, we may require credit or debit card account information. By submitting your credit or debit card account information through the Subscription Services, you expressly consent to the sharing of such information with third-party payment processors for the sole purpose of billing you for the Subscription Services.

## **Legal**

We may disclose your information to third parties if we determine that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to (a) comply with the law; (b) protect any person from death or serious bodily injury; (c) prevent fraud or abuse of Crystal or our users; or (d) protect Crystal’s property rights.

## **Change of Control**

If we are involved in a reorganization, merger, acquisition or sale of our assets, your information may be transferred as part of that deal. We will notify you (for example, via a message to the email address associated with your account) of any such deal and outline your choices in that event. We may revise this Privacy Policy from time to time, and will post the most current version on our website. If a revision meaningfully reduces your rights, we will notify you. We will comply with applicable laws and regulations to the extent changes to this Privacy Policy require your consent.

If you are a resident of the European Union (“EU”) or the United Kingdom (“UK”), you may have additional rights, as detailed in this section. To process your Personal Data, we rely on the following legal bases: (i) pursuant to your consent, which is provided by acknowledging your agreement with our Terms of Service and this Privacy Policy when you sign up for our Subscription Services (note that such consent is affirmatively given by clicking the applicable check boxes; we will never presume that you have provided consent); (ii) to perform the contract we have with you to provide the Subscription Services; (iii) for compliance with legal obligations to which we are or to which we may become subject (including tax obligations, and requests from law enforcement agencies or other competent authorities with jurisdiction over us and our Subscription Services); and (iv) for the purposes of our legitimate interests in providing the Subscription Services to you, making suggestions to you regarding service offerings, monitoring the Subscription Services for fraud or misuse, ensuring the functionality of our Subscription Services, and making assumptions and predictions about third parties based solely on publicly available information for which such third parties do not have reasonable expectations of privacy.

To the extent that you have provided consent for us to process certain of your Personal Data, you may withdraw your consent at any time. To withdraw your consent, please follow the contact instructions set forth under the Section of this Privacy Policy titled Contact. You may also contact us at any time to request that we cease some or all of the processing of your Personal Data, whether or not such processing was the result of your specific consent or some other identified legal basis. It is your choice whether you share Personal Data with us, and it is your choice whether you revoke consent at any time or otherwise request us to cease processing your information. There is no legal consequence to you if your refrain from providing or otherwise revoke consent to our processing of your Personal Data. However, please note that our ability to provide the Subscription Services and other services to you may be impacted if you do not share certain Personal Data with us in connection with your use of the Subscription Services or other services.

You may request that we confirm whether or not we are processing your Personal Data, and you may request access at any time to your Personal Data over which we have control. You may also request information about our processing of Personal Data, including the type of Personal Data processed and the reasons for such processing. There are no costs to you associated with these requests; however we may charge reasonable fees for administrative costs for excessive or repetitive requests. You may request that we change, alter, amend, or update your Personal Data and you may request that we refrain from processing certain information if it is inaccurate or unlawfully held. You may request a copy of your Personal Data for transfer to another entity. You may also, at any time, request that we delete or erase your Personal Data, unless we are required by applicable law to retain such information or have other legitimate grounds for continuing to process your Personal Data. You may also object at any time to our use of your Personal Data to provide direct marketing. To exercise any of the rights described above, please follow the contact instructions under the Section of this Privacy Policy titled “Contact”.

Have questions or concerns about Crystal, our Services and privacy? Want us to delete, alter, update, or change any information we have about you? Contact us at hello@crystalknows.com.

## ‍
